<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>docker-swarm on Jay Vala</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/tags/docker-swarm/</link><description>Recent content in docker-swarm on Jay Vala</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2020, Jay Vala. Theme - Origin by Andrey Parfenov</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jdvala.github.io/tags/docker-swarm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Rancher to deploy Feel Good News app backend on Kubernets</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2020-10-06-using-rancher-feel-good-news/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2020-10-06-using-rancher-feel-good-news/</guid><description>TL;DR: this deployment was overkill but I learned a lot. Hats off to all the DevOps out there.
Some days ago I launched an app on both iOS and Andriod with help from a friend (frontend is not my cup of tea). The backend, however, I wrote in python. The app is based on a very simple concept, use a sentiment analysis algorithm to filter out sad, negative, and gloomy news from the news feed.</description></item><item><title>Orchesrating Docker Swarm</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2020-10-01-orchestrating-docker-swarm/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2020-10-01-orchestrating-docker-swarm/</guid><description>Initalize a swarm on a node which you can prefer, to create a manager. The architecture of the docker swarm orchestration is that it has a manager node (which is a whole node or computer). Then there are worker nodes which can be controlled or manage by the manager node.
(image: https://blog.knoldus.com/orchestration-with-docker-swarm/)
In the diagram above the swam manager is a node which is used to control the swam nodes. In general terminology swarm manager is refered to as manager and the swarm nodes are refered to as workers or worker nodes.</description></item></channel></rss>