<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>shell on Jay Vala</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/tags/shell/</link><description>Recent content in shell on Jay Vala</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2020, Jay Vala. Theme - Origin by Andrey Parfenov</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jdvala.github.io/tags/shell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Create and Manage Python virtual environment</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2021-04-25-easily-manage-and-create-virtual-environments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2021-04-25-easily-manage-and-create-virtual-environments/</guid><description>In any fast paced AI startup, developers and data scientist have to manage a lot of repositories. For me personally, I manage 3 or sometimes 4 repositories at a time and switching between virtual environemts for these repositories is pain according to me, writing source deactivate to first deactivate the exisiting environment and then activating it by cding into the repo and source env/bin/activate.
To avoid this I wrote a function that will ease this pain.</description></item><item><title>How to make your system remind you to drink water and sit straight</title><link>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2021-04-20-stay-healty-linux-reminds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jdvala.github.io/posts/2021-04-20-stay-healty-linux-reminds/</guid><description>During this pandemic we have all been working from home, which has its own merits but also has its own demerits. In the office we behave in a certian way as we have our colleague in the same sitting area, but at home we are in our own comfort zone.
Personally, I have very bad habbit of forgetting to drink water when I work, in office I used to see my colleagues drinking water, which reminded me to drink water as well.</description></item></channel></rss>